JOSHUA PALAMUTTAM

https://github.com/joshpal
97 \diamond https://Joshua Palamuttam.com San Jose, CA 95138

 $(408) \cdot 841 \cdot 6194 \diamond joshpal97@gmail.com$

SUMMARY

A highly-motivated computer professional, who graduated with a Computer Science degree from Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology '19, with the enthusiasm to accept new challenges. The software engineering positions I have been in have given me hands-on work experience working on application design, development, and quality assurance using agile practices, and writing clean code.

EDUCATION

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology

2015 - 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

EXPERIENCE

Kaiser Permanente Genetics

February 2020 - Present

Junior Dot Net Analyst, San Jose, CA

- · Main purpose was to do RD for different applications used by the Genetics Department
- \cdot Responsibilities for this job include gathering requirements along with developing and supporting applications
- · Made applications with the Kaiser tech stack of primarily .Net Core MVC applications, with a SQL Database
- · Occasionally made Batch Files, or Excel VBA scripts to aid Lab Technicians in thier duties DMI

 May 2019

Software Engineer, Indianapolis, IN

May 2019 - February 2020

- · Helped create a POC for Kar Global to optimize lot operations at a car auction site, using Angular, Node.js, AWS serverless, SQL (2 months)
- · Helped build a physics engine called ISCAAN for Allison Transmission to simulate a transmission (7 months)
- · The majority of Allison Transmission's proprietary math was done using C++, which was then passed to a Angular, .Net Core, SQL stack, using Entity Framework Core
- · Because of ISCAAN's large nature, the project was designed to use a hexagonal software architecture
- · Built Microsoft Teams Chat bot for DMI, using LUIS an Azure Cognitive Service (NLP) with a .Net Core back end (1 month)
- · All projects used Azure Devops to adhere to SAFe agile practices, such as CI/CD, unit and integration testing

PROJECTS

Compile.io (Angular, Spring Boot, MongoDb, Docker)

2018-2019

- · My Senior Project, tasked to build a scalable website that automatically grades student submitted code
- · Code was submitted through the Angular front-end, taken to our Java Spring backend, processed in a docker container, and stored in MongoDB.
- · Gathered requirements from professors, and wrote documentation that can be viewed in my github
- · Followed Agile methodologies, with CI/CD, 2 week sprints, feature branching strategy, and unit testing

Stock Market Analysis through Twitter (Python)

Spring 2019

- · The purpose of this project was to figure out how a companys twitter handle and companys CEO twitter handle affected the companys stock
- · Performed Latent Semantic Analysis on tweets for those twitter handles
- · Pre-processed data by removing stop words, duplicate tweets, and special characters
- · Used cross-validation, and Naive Bayes to predict the Stock Market
- · The stock data was recieved through quandl, and the tweets were recieved through tweepy

Full stack website, College Cookbook (Javascript, Firebase, MongoDB)

Fall 2017

- · The website can be found at this link: https://college-cookbook-jkl.firebaseapp.com/login.html or github
- · Developed and Integrated a MongoDB database for the back end and deployed front end through Firebase
- · Features: posting to twitter, emailing recipes, inputting recipes into the database, and secure login

SKILLS

Programming Languages
JavaScript, Typescript, C#, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, Python
Angular, Node.js, Spring, .Net Core, Entity Framework Core

Tools AWS, Azure Devops, Docker, Git, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

Certifications AWS Cloud Practitioner, SAFe 4.6